Mss.Rec.150 Mss.Rec.150
American Philosophical Society
Iroqouis material
1941, 1945, 1948
Mss.Rec.150
American Philosophical Society
14.0 Item(s) 14 phonograph discs
14 sound discs (2 hr., 20 min.): analog, 78 rpm; 12 in.
Buck, George
Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
General, Alexander J. (Deskaheh after 1925)
General, Jack
Green, George, Mrs.
Green, George
John, Willie
Johnny John, Chauncey
Jones, Albert
Styres, Edward
Thomas, David
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by William Fenton in 1990. The records are copies made at the Library of Congress from original field recordings made on a Presto Disk Recorder.
Related Archival Materials
William N. Fenton Papers (Mss.Ms.Coll.20)
Conditions Governing Access
This material has access restritions. Please consult a curator for details.
Cayuga Indians--Music; Iroquois Indians--Music; Iroquois Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Onondaga Indians--Music; Seneca Indians--Music; Sound recordings
- Audio recordings
  - Test strip with Snipe Song, 1945-04-29; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:51; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
    Scope and Contents note
    Original record 1, side A.
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Phonograph record) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Iroquois Indians--Music; Six Nations Indian Reserve No. 40 (Ont.)
  - Greeting and Ado'wa when opening ceremony at Longhouse, 1945-04-29; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:57; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Thomas, David
    Iroquois Indians--Music; Iroquois Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Onondaga Indians--Music; Six Nations Indian Reserve No. 40 (Ont.)
  - Seventh Song of Condolence, used at Syracuse, 1945-04-29; 01-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:20; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Thomas, David
  - Seventh Song of Condolence, used at Syracuse, 1945-04-29; 01-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:25; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Thomas, David
    Original record 1, side B.
  - 1st of Six Songs used at Canada, 1945-04-29; 01-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:35; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Thomas, David
  - Six Songs, Ahiyaknigainage: 1-2, 1945; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:58; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Thomas, David
    Original record 2, side A.
  - Six Songs, Ahiyaknigainage: Great Hymn, 1945; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:10; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Thomas, David
  - Six Songs, Ahiyaknigainage: 6th Song, 1945; 02-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:53; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Thomas, David
    Original record 2, side B.
  - Reply of Cayugas, 1945; 02-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:30; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Thomas, David
  - Over the Great Forest, 1945; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:58; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; General, Alex
    Original record 3, side A.
    Cayuga Indians--Music; Iroquois Indians--Music; Iroquois Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Six Nations Indian Reserve No. 40 (Ont.)
  - Over the Great Forest, 1945; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:58; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; General, Alex
    Original record 3, side B.
  - Athahinon?keh: Going on the Road, Eulogy of the Founders, 1945; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:20; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Thomas, David
    Original record 4, side A.
  - Welcome at Woods Edge, 1945; 04-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:22; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; General, Alex
    Original record 4, side B.
  - The songs of hadiye'qwiyaneh to renew the Little Water Medicine, Group I, songs 1-8, 1941-02-17; 05-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:08; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Johnny John, Chauncey
    Original record 57, side A.
    Allegany Indian Reservation (N.Y.); Iroquois Indians--Music; Iroquois Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Seneca Indians--Music
  - The songs of hadiye'qwiyaneh to renew the Little Water Medicine, Group I, songs 9-16, 1941-02-17; 05-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:42; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Johnny John, Chauncey
    Original record 57, side B.
  - The songs of hadiye'qwiyaneh to renew the Little Water Medicine, Group I, songs 17-24, 1941-02-17; 06-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:35; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Johnny John, Chauncey
    Original record 58, side A.
  - The songs of hadiye'qwiyaneh to renew the Little Water Medicine, Group II, songs 1-7, 1941-02-17; 06-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:10; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Johnny John, Chauncey
    Original record 58, side B.
  - The songs of hadiyen?gwa?ye:ni to renew the Little Water Medicine, Group II, songs 8-13, 1941-02-17; 07-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:14; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Johnny John, Chauncey
    Original record 59, side A.
  - The songs of hadiyen?gwa?ye:ni to renew the Little Water Medicine, Group II, songs 14-20, 1941-02-17; 07-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:22; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Johnny John, Chauncey
    Original record 59, side B.
  - The songs of hadiyen?gwa?ye:ni to renew the Little Water Medicine, Group II, songs 21-26, 1941-02-17; 08-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:01; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Johnny John, Chauncey
    Original record 60, side A.
  - The songs of hadiyen?gwa?ye:ni to renew the Little Water Medicine, Group III, songs 1-6, 1941-02-17; 08-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:03; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Johnny John, Chauncey
    Original record 60, side B.
  - The songs of hadiyen?gwa?ye:ni to renew the Little Water Medicine, Group III, songs 7-12, 1941-02-17; 09-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:01; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Johnny John, Chauncey
    Original record 61, side A.
  - The songs of hadiyen?gwa?ye:ni to renew the Little Water Medicine, Group IV, songs 1-6, 1941-02-17; 09-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:00; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Johnny John, Chauncey
    Original record 61, side B.
  - The songs of hadiyen?gwa?ye:ni to renew the Little Water Medicine, Group IV, songs 7-13, 1941-02-17; 10-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:00; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Johnny John, Chauncey
    Original record 62, side A.
  - The songs of hadiyen?gwa?ye:ni to renew the Little Water Medicine, Group IV, songs 14-24, 1941-02-17; 10-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:16; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Johnny John, Chauncey
    Original record 62, side B.
  - Gane'o'q Drum Dance, 1945-11-24; 11-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:18; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Johnny John, Chauncey; Jones, Albert
    Original record 25, side A.
    Allegany Indian Reservation (N.Y.); Iroquois Indians--Music; Seneca Indians--Music
  - Corn Dance, 1945-11-24; 11-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:13; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Johnny John, Chauncey; Jones, Albert
    Original record 25, side B.
  - Fish Dance of Olden Times, 1945; 12-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:27; Buck, George; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Styres, Edward
    Original record 12, side A.
    Cayuga Indians--Music; Iroquois Indians--Music; Six Nations Indian Reserve No. 40 (Ont.)
  - Cayuga Fish Dance, 1945; 12-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:21; Buck, George; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Styres, Edward
    Original record 12, side B.
  - Old Time Women's Dance, 1945-11-16; 13-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:07; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Green, George; John, Willie
    Original record 5, side A.
  - Individual Songs: Willie John and George Green, 1945-11-16; 13-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:44; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Green, George; John, Willie
    Original record 5, side B.
  - Individual Songs: Mrs. George Green, 1945-11-16; 13-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:46; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Green, George, Mrs.
  - Garter Dance, 1948-05; 14-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:03; Buck, George; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Styres, Edward
    Original record 11, side A.
  - Pigeon Song, 1948-05; 14-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:46; Buck, George; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; General, Jack; Styres, Edward
    Original record 11, side B.